Floyd Glass Navy Recruiting Literature Collection, 1941-1949
University of Houston Libraries
Floyd Glass Navy Recruiting Literature Collection
1941-1949
Glass, Floyd
1970-002
This collection is composed entirely of U. S. Navy recruiting literature from 1941-1949. Included are booklets, pamphlets, broadsides, posters, promotional materials and some miscellaneous response cards.The collection was donated to the University of Houston Libraries by Floyd Glass, a Houston resident, book collector, and retired Naval officer.
488 items; 13 boxes
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
Floyd Glass served in the United States Navy for several years. During World War II, he was stationed abroad in England for some time.
After his retirement from the Navy, Glass and his wife Marjorie moved to Houston. During this time he assembled a fine collection of books on English literature and history, as well as illustrated books and books with unusual bindings. This collection was donated to the University of Houston Libraries in the late 1960s.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed entirely of U. S. Navy recruiting literature from 1941-1949. Included are booklets, pamphlets, broadsides, posters, promotional materials and some miscellaneous response cards. Materials have been sorted by type of material. Materials for recruiting WAVES (the women's counterpart to the U. S. Navy) have been separated from materials recruiting men.
The 61 booklets (items with several pages), and 129 pamphlets (items made from one or two folded sheets) are arranged alphabetically by title. The miscellaneous items (108 items), which include promotional materials and response cards, are arranged alphabetically by folder heading.
Posters and other broadsheets (190 items, total) have been sorted so that all duplicate materials are together. These materials are arranged at the container level. One box of the posters includes items which were drymounted to acid-free board. These items have been kept together, as have posters and broadsheets which are geared toward recruiting WAVES.
For additional materials held in Special Collections on World War II and the U. S. Navy, see the Cruiser Houston Collection and the William A. Bernrieder Collection.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects(Persons)
Glass, Floyd
Subjects
World War, 1939-1945; United States. Navy Recruiting.
Formats
Pamphlets; Broadsides; Posters
Acquisition
The collection was given by the widow of Mr. Floyd Glass, Mrs. Marjorie Glass.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Detailed Description
- Booklets
  - Facts about the submarine service., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Facts and figures of naval service., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fill the fleet., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Going back to civilian life., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - How you can win your Navy wings., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - How your college can help you be a naval officer., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jobs in naval aviation., undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Joint Armed Forces prestige campaign., 1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Life in the peacetime Navy., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Life in the peacetime Navy., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Life in the peacetime Navy., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Men make the Navy., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Music in the Navy., undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Naval aviation., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Navy airman., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Navy as a peacetime career., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Navy educational program., 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Navy recruit., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Navy recruit., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Navy services to help its contractors., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Officer's career in the peacetime Navy., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Officer's career in the U. S. Navy., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Officer's career in the U. S. Navy., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Padres of the sea., undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Peacetime Navy's recruitment policy in high schools., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Presentation for civic groups: Naval recruiting., undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Re: Officer commissions in the United States., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Schools and rates for Navy men., 1944 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - See action now with the submarine service., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Task force guide., undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - U. S. Navy war photographs., 1945 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Wear wings of Navy gold., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - What about the supply corps?, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - What kind of job can I get in the Navy?, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Young men needed in Navy radar., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Your future in the Navy., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Your Navy., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Your opportunities in the submarine service., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Booklets/WAVES
  - How to serve your country in the WAVES., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Join the Waves., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mightiest Navy in the world faces an urgent need., undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Story of you in Navy blue., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - WAVES wanted., 1944 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Pamphlets
  - Announcing valuable new benefits for men enlisting or re-enlisting in the regular Navy., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint for your future., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Can you unzip a Navy ship?, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Constant vigilance assures peace., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Did you know., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Don't forget your Navy ties., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Financial report to a bluejacket., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fly with the fleet., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fly with the fleet., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - For men only., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Keys to your future., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Let's go Navy., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Let's GO NAVY., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Let's GO NAVY for travel and adventure., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Let's keep in touch in the Naval Air Reserve., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Memo to stenographers typists and clerks., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Naval Reserve offers you retirement benefits., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Navy athletics., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Navy offers you a $5000 education in electronics...free., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Peacetime Navy is a great life., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - See Pearl Harbor work in Hawaii., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Stay in school., undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Submarine service in the Naval Reserve., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - To an old shipmate., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - U. S. Navy material in our library., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - U. S. N. R. -- A community asset., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - What's your answer., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - What's your Navy dollar worth?, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - When does 1 = 3.9?, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - When does 3.9 = 1?, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Win your Navy wings of gold., undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Your career in electronics., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Your commission in Naval aviation., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Pamphlets/WAVES.
  - Chance that you may never get again., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Facts about the WAVES and the SPARS., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - How you can help your Navy man., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Navy Nurse Corps offers you more., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Waves USN., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - You can help bring your Navy man home., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous
  - Broken service., 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Career analysis for junior executives., 1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hats off!, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Looking ahead., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Navy V-1 Field Officers' manual., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Plan now for your future., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Radio play for WAVES recruiting., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Recruitment cards., 1942-1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Recuritment response cards., 1942-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Requirements for enlistment., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rise and shine, sailors., undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Something for the girls., 1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Suggested mayor's proclamation., 1947 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - To the post commander., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Training packet., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Victory volunteer certificate., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - What's ahead for them?, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - When will you retire?, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Posters
  - Posters, (24 items) (Box 8)
  - Posters, (94 items) (Box 9)
  - Posters, (9 items) (Box 10)
  - Posters, (34 items) (Box 11)
  - Posters, (15 items) (Box 12)
  - Posters/WAVES, (14 items) (Box 13)